# Hugo Pineda

Full-stack Software Engineer
Temuco, Chile
hpineda83@gmail.com
+56974273675
hugo.pineda.83 (Skype)



#### Extract

Full-stack Software Engineer with more than 9 years of professional experience developing software for the web, with strong experience with Python (Django), PostgreSQL and Javascript (React, AngularJS, jQuery).

Vast experience as remote employee, open for relocation.

Eligible for H-1B1 visa for chilean citizens.

# Experience

# Software Engineer at CareLinx (San Bruno, CA, August 2015 - December 2017)

Working as a remote software engineer from Chile with the team in San Bruno, CA. Implementing the new design of the website and migrating the existing Django application to React/Django Rest.

Main contributions include:

- Website revamp to be 100% mobile responsive, compatible webview in iOS and Android app, cross-client compatible emails
- Real time messaging system for CareLinx Users, using Firebase as the backend.
- Task list module with email alerts and push notifications on the iOS and Android apps.
- Advanced scheduling for the tasks including recurring tasks on different time spans.
- Main engineer for timesheet and invoicing, including smart overtime calculations, PDF generation and email alerts.
- Integration with HomeWork Solutions.
- Integration with Backgrounds Online

Technologies: Django, Django Rest Framework, React, React Native, Firebase, PostgreSQL

# Software Engineer at LawLogix (Phoenix, AZ / Temuco, Chile, April 2012 - July 2015)

Participated in one year J-1 exchange visitor training program at LawLogix in Phoenix, AZ. Successfully ported legacy code from existing LawLogix's product to Python using Django web framework.

Worked on the architectural design of a new company project, implementing a 3-tier application using Django Rest Framework and an AngularJS client. Main achievement is 100% coverage on unit test for both Python and Javascript projects.

Implemented test-driven development and trained new developers.

Technologies: Django Rest Framework, Celery, PostgreSQL, AngularJS, Grunt, Karma

# **Lead Programmer at Foxido** (Santiago, Chile, September 2011 – February 2012)

Designed and implemented the site for a startup company that created an online marketplace for local services.

Technologies: Django, MySQL, jQuery

# **Software Developer at** *Derco* (Santiago, Chile, March 2011 – August 2011)

Implemented an e-commerce system for the existing product catalogs (auto parts), connecting the client system to the main SAP services.

Technologies: ASP.NET, MS SQL Server, jQuery

#### Software Developer at AreaWeb (Santiago, Chile, November 2010 – February 2011)

Created and developed one project for a private finance company. This project provides a friendly user interface for existing web services on said company.

Technologies: Django, ASP.NET, jQuery

# **Software Developer at** *Quintec* (Santiago, Chile, June 2010 – November 2010)

Contributed in both server and client side development for a government project for birth control system on public medical hospitals.

Technologies: ASP.NET, MS SQL Server, ¡Query

# **Software Developer at** *TIDE* (Temuco, Chile, March 2008 – June 2010)

Participated in numerous educational and commercial software projects. Main achievements are statistical data reports system for a private College and online catalog for educational resources.

Technologies: Django, jQuery, FusionCharts, PHP, Magento, MySQL, Adobe Flex

**Education** 

# Civil Industrial Engineer with a concentration in Computer Science 2002 to 2008

Universidad de La Frontera (Temuco, Chile)

About me

I am passionate about technology, sports and healthy lifestyle. Full marathon runner and amateur soccer player.